Preliminary Guide to the Clarence Day, Jr. Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Clarence Shepard Day papers
1894-1947
MS 1094
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
The papers consist of letters written by Clarence Day, many with ink drawings, to family and friends on personal matters and on business relating to the Class of 1896 of Yale University, of which Day was secretary. Also included is the record book of the Raleigh Pipe Club (1894-1907) and miscellaneous newspaper clippings.
Day, Clarence, 1874-1935
Biographical / Historical
The son of a stockbroker, Clarence Day, Jr. was born in New York City, on November 18, 1874. He was educated at St. Paul's School in Concord, New Hampshire, before attending Yale College. Upon graduating in 1896, Day followed his father into the stock market, but quickly came to dislike it and joined the navy. After being stricken with arthritis, Day had to leave the navy. Bound to crutches and a wheelchair, he began to write poems and books with some success. It was not until the last year of his life, however, that one of his books, Life with Father, became widely successful, winning awards and reaching the top of nonfiction best-seller lists. Day died of pneumonia on December 28, 1935, in New York City.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of letters written by Clarence Day, many with ink drawings, to family and friends on personal matters and on business relating to the Class of 1896 of Yale University, of which Day was secretary. Also included is the record book of the Raleigh Pipe Club (1894-1907) and miscellaneous newspaper clippings.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Alexander, Eugene D.; Day, Clarence, 1874-1935; Day, George Parmly, 1876-1959; Day, Sherman, 1806-1884; Day, Wilhelmine Octavia Johnson; Fisher, Alice Gifford Agnew; Johnston, Henry Selden; Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1874-1958; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1896; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Raleigh Pipe Club
- Inventory
  - Correspondence
    - Adams, John (Jack) Chester (Accession 1992-M-091), 1908, 1911, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alexander, Eugene D., 1910, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Clark, W. Hashimura, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Day, George Parmly, 1927, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Day, Sherman, 1910-1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Day, Wilhelmine Octavia (Johnson) (Mrs. George P.), 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Fisher, Alice (Agnew), 1905 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Gregory, Herbert E., 1905-1912, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Johnson, Frederick B., 1911, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Johnston, Henry Selden, 1901-1902, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified [letter concerns Anson Phelps Stokes], undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Record book of Raleigh Pipe Club, Yale University, 1894-1907 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Printed articles by Day, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1916, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 14)